底比斯 公元前3067年
五千年前
Five thousand years ago,
一名骁勇擅战的武士 魔蝎大帝
a fierce warrior known as the Scorpion King...
率领大军企图征服世界
led a great army on a campaign to conquer the known world.
经历了长达七年的战役
After a vicious campaign which lasted seven long years,
魔蝎大帝的军队大败
the Scorpion King and his army were defeated...
一路溃退至神圣的沙漠 阿姆谢
and driven deep into the sacred desert of Ahm Shere.
一个接着一个 他们慢慢地倒了下去
One by one, they slowly perished under the scorching sun...
只剩下这名伟大的武士
until only the great warrior himself was left alive.
临死之前...
Near death,
魔蝎大帝向死神阿努比斯立誓
the Scorpion King made a pact with the dark god Anubis...
只要阿努比斯肯饶他一命 让他征服敌人
that if Anubis would spare his life and let him conquer his enemies,
他愿意交出他的灵魂
he would give him his soul.
阿努比斯答应了他的请求 饶他不死
Anubis accepted his offer and spared his life.
阿姆谢绿洲
魔蝎大帝率领阿努比斯的军队
Anubis gave the Scorpion King command of his army,
大军如洪水般摧毁了一切
and like an evil flood, they washed away all that lay before them.
在他达成目的以后
When his task was done
阿努比斯按照约定取走他的灵魂
Anubis forced the Scorpion King to serve him for all time.
他的军队则回到原来的沙地之下
His army was returned to the sands from whence they came,
他们耐心的在地下等待着再度重返人间
where they wait, silently, to be awakened once again.
1933年 埃及
艾力克斯?
Alex?
你以为木乃伊复活了吗?
What were you thinking, a mummy had come back to life?
我有空再告诉你
I'll tell you a story some time.
你下来干嘛?我不是叫你待在上面
What are you doing down here? I told you to wait for us up in the temple.
- 可是我...  - 别可是 下面很危险
- But, Dad, I saw...   - No "buts." It's dangerous down here, Alex.
- 可是我看到你的刺青  - 看到什么?
- But I saw your tattoo.   - You saw what?
门口的墙上有一样的螺旋形装饰
On a wall by the entrance. There's a cartouche just like it.
有金字塔、有眼睛 还有帝王 完全一样
With the pyramid and the eye and the two kings and everything.
- 真的?  - 真的
- Really?   - Yeah.
好 我等一下再上去看
Okay, well, I'll be up to take a look at that in a minute.
还有 我要你回上面等
In the meantime, I want you to wait for us up there. But... But...
东西拿好 我等一下上去找你
No, pick up your stuff, and I'll see you up in the temple.
去
Go.
快去
Go on.
那我要做什么?
And... And what shall I do?
我不知道 随便你
I don't know. Surprise me.
盖个好一点的捕鼠机
Build a better mousetrap.
好
Okay.
趁你妈忙着挖别人的墓
While your mother goes and desecrates another tomb.
走开
Go away.
那有毒的
Those are poisonous, you know.
除非被它们咬到
Only if they bite you.
怎么回事?
What was all that about?
没什么 艾力克斯有东西要我看
Oh, nothing. Alex wanted to show me something.
我发誓
I swear,
这小鬼越来越像你
the kid gets more and more like you every day.
你是指越来越有魅力、越可爱
What, you mean more attractive, sweet and...
还有越来越迷人?
devilishly charming?
不是 他要把我逼疯了
No, he's driving me crazy.
做到哪了?
Now, where were we?
锤子和凿子
Hammer and chisel.
好啦!好啦!照你的方法
All right, all right! Let's do it your way.
谢谢
Thank you.
自从我开始梦到这里
Ever since I had that dream,
我心里...就一直想个不停
this place is all I can think about.
自从你开始做梦 我就没好好睡过
Ever since you had that dream, I haven't had a decent night of sleep.
我觉得我以前来过这里
I feel like I've been here before.
我知道我有来过这里
I know I've been here before.
伊芙 这地方至少三千年没人来过
Evy, nobody's been here before. Not in at least 3,000 years.
除了这些家伙
Except for these guys.
那我为什么会知道路?
Then how do I seem to know exactly where I'm going?
走吧!
Let's go.
请问...有人在家吗?
Knock, knock. Anybody home?
你们两个在这边找找看
You two check out that stuff, see if it's there.
我去搞定欧康纳他们
I'll sort out the O'Connells.
知道吗?再快一点 你就可以写字了
You know, if you move that fast enough, you can almost write your name.
我看到东西了
I just had a vision.
和我梦到的一样 但是更真
It was... It was like my dream, but it was real.
我好像回到了古代
It was like I was actually here in ancient times.
真是那样的话 麻烦你告诉我这门怎么开
Well, if you actually were here, could you show me how to open this thing?
拿着
Hold this.
我被你吓到了
All right, now you're starting to scare me.
我自己也是
Now I'm starting to scare myself.
这是什么?全是一堆垃圾
What is this? Look at the state of this rubbish.
搞不清楚状况的埃及人
Those Egyptians never had a clue.
根本就是一堆便宜货 我的妈
It's all chintz and stuff. Look at that.
烂陶器 还有没用的废物
Cheap pottery, this. Ancient rubbish.
杰克 有东西打到我的头
Jacques, something's hit me head!
闭嘴 史皮威
Shut up, Spivey.
这地方有诅咒
This place is cursed.
不要把神给吵醒了
We do not want to wake the gods.
这是魔蝎大帝的徽章
That's the emblem of the Scorpion King.
他应该只是虚构的人物
He's supposed to be pure myth.
以前从来没有找到他的记录
No... No trace of him has ever been found before.
没有史前器物 也没有文献资料
No artifacts, no archival evidence.
也许他们不希望他被找到
Maybe they didn't want anybody to find him.
我们打开看看
Let's open this.
伊芙 我觉得这样做不太好
Evy, I don't have a real good feeling about this.
只是一个箱子 打开箱子不会有坏处
It's only a chest. No harm ever came from opening a chest.
是啊!读书不会有坏处 结果怎么样
Right, and no harm ever came from reading a book. Remember how that went?
别这样 我们不能半途而废
We can't stop now.
记住 我是有道理的
Just remember, I was the voice of reason here.
偶尔有
For once.
垃圾
Rubbish.
废物 便宜货 只有一半...
Dreck. Chintz. Only half of this...
天哪!痛死我了
God, that hurt!
老婆 用你的方法
Hon? Let's do it your way.
死神之镯
The bracelet of Anubis.
交给我处理
I'll take care of this.
我的天
Oh, my God.
现在放回去有用吗?
It's a bit late for that!
放进你的背包里
Put it in your rucksack.
不要 把它放回去
I got a better idea. Let's leave it here.
已经来不及了
I think it's a bit late for that!
上面写什么?
What's it say?
凡打扰手镯者 必饮尼罗河之水
"He who disturbs this bracelet shall drink from the Nile."
听起来还好嘛
That doesn't sound too bad.
小子 杰克会好好修理你的
Jacques's gonna make a nice fillet out of you, my son.
糟了
Oh, please. Please.
史皮威、杰克 我们快闪
Spivey! Jacques! Let's get the hell outta here!
快走
Come on!
伊芙 这次糟了
This is bad, Evy!
我们以前也碰过 这次更糟
We've had bad before! This is worse!
妈、爸 你们听我解释
Mom, Dad, I can explain everything.
哈姆纳塔 亡灵之城
亡灵黑经起死回生
The Book of the Dead gives life.
而太阳金经...
And the Book of the Living...
转生为死
takes life away.
我以为那是我的工作
I thought that was my job.
我们快找到了
We're getting close.
拿到了吗?
Did you acquire it?
就快要找到了
We're getting very close.
我们找到了
We've found him.
找到他了 我们找到他了
We've found him! We've found him!
让开 别挡路
Step aside here. Out of the way!
伊莫顿
Imhotep.
是他 是伊莫顿
It's him. It's Imhotep.
现在我们要招回他的僧侣
Now we must raise those that serve him.
滚开 别挡着我
Get out of my way.
让开 不然我一枪打死你
Get out of my way, or I'm gonna shoot you in the face.
他是说真的 他以前干过
He means it. He shot someone before.
东西拿来
Give it to me.
出了一点状况
Opportunity passed us by.
我们需要那只手镯
We need that bracelet.
我们要有手镯才能开始
And we need it before it opens.
够了
Enough.
哈夫兹
My dear Hafez,
我说过应该交给我来处理
I told you I should have handled it.
我不希望你的过去让事情变得更复杂
I told you I should have handled it. I did not want your past history to cloud the issue.
别担心 我们会搞定 我们知道在哪
We know where it is. We'll take care of it.
不用 我们自己会搞定
No, we'll take care of it.
我有别的事要你去办
I have a different chore for you now.
手镯在哪?
Where is the bracelet?
在去伦敦的路上
It's on its way to merry old London.
那我们就去伦敦
Then London is where we must go.
我认为手镯可以带路去失落的绿洲 阿姆谢
I think the bracelet is some sort of guide to the lost oasis of Ahm Shere.
伊芙 我知道你在想什么
Evy, I know what you're thinking,
答案是"不行"
and the answer is no.
我们才刚到家
We just got home.
就是有这点好处 我们不用收拾行李了
That's the beauty of it. We're already packed.
可不可以掰一个更好的理由?
Why don't you just give me one good reason.
那只是一座绿洲
It's just an oasis,
老公
darling.
美丽
A beautiful,
刺激
exciting,
浪漫的...
romantic...
绿洲
oasis.
那种有白沙滩、棕榈树
The kind with the white, sandy beach and the palm trees...
还有清澈的湖水?
and the cool, clear, blue water and...
我们可以喝那种上面插一把雨伞的饮料
We could have some of those big drinks with the little umbrellas.
听起来很棒
Sounds good.
听起来太棒了 有什么风险?
Sounds too good. What's the catch?
有可能是阿努比斯军队的安息地
Supposedly it's the resting place of Anubis's army.
看吧!我就知道没这么简单
See? I knew there's a catch.
我怎么会知道?猜也猜得到
There's always a catch. And let me guess.
军队是由那个魔蝎大帝指挥
It was commanded by that Scorpion King guy?
对 但是他每五千年才会醒过来
Yes, but he only awakens once every 5,000 years.
而且要是没人杀死他 他就会摧毁全世界
Right. And if someone doesn't kill him, he's gonna wipe out the world.
你怎么知道?
How did you know?
我不知道 但是每次都这样
I didn't. But that's always the story.
最后一支抵达阿姆谢的远征队
The last known expedition to actually reach Ahm Shere
是拉美士四世在三千年前派出去的
was sent by Ramses the Fourth over 3,000 years ago.
他派了一千多人出去
He sent over a thousand men.
但是没有一个人回来
And none of them was ever seen again.
- 你怎么知道?  - 我不知道 但是每次都这样
- How did you know?   - I didn't. But that's always the story.
- 我提过纯金的金字塔吗?  - 第二次了
- Did I mention there was a pyramid of gold?   - Twice.
亚历山大大帝派军队去寻找阿姆谢
Alexander the Great sent troops in search of it.
- 祝他好运  - 还有凯撒
- Hooray for him.   - So did Caesar.
- 你看他的下场  - 还有拿破仑
- Yeah, look what happened to his career.   - And Napoleon.
不过 我们比他聪明 也比他高
But we're smarter than him. And taller too.
没错 所以我们一定会找到
Exactly. That's why we're gonna find it.
因为我们够高?
Because we're taller?
所以我才会爱上你
That's why I love you.
少来了
Nice try.
妈
Mom!
箱子要怎么办?
What do I do with this chest?
死箱子妈的重死人了
This sucker weighs a goddang ton.
艾力克斯 不准说脏话
Alex, watch your language!
箱子非常的重
Rather weighty, this.
你是六个星期前开始做那个怪梦的?
Evy, that first weird dream of yours was exactly six weeks ago, right?
是啊!那有什么关系吗?
I think so, yes. But what's that got to do with anything?
那时候正好是埃及的新年
It just happens to coincide with Egyptian New Year.
蝎 年
没错耶!真巧
That's right. What a coincidence.
也许
Maybe.
我觉得我们该小心一点
All I'm saying is, let's be cautious.
你要是出事 我永远不会原谅我自己
If anything happened to you, I would never forgive myself.
我在意的只有你和艾力克斯
You and Alex are the only thing that matter to me.
其实...
Well,
班桥学者一直在求我
the Bembridge scholars have been begging me...
管理大英博物馆
to run the British Museum.
天啊!要怎么脱掉?
cripes, how do you get this thing off?
我今天亲过你没?
Have I kissed you today?
我最讨厌你这样
I hate it when you do that.
为什么?
Why?
害我什么都答应
Makes me feel like agreeing to anything.
- 真的?  - 恩
- Anything?   - Mm-hmm.
那不是我的内衣
Those knickers are not mine.
强纳森
Jonathan.
儿子 乖五分钟行不行?
Hey, Alex, behave yourself for five minutes.
没问题
You betcha.
回家高兴吗?
Happy to be home?
非常高兴
Couldn't be happier.
今年是蝎年
It's the year of the scorpion.
- 酷哦!  - 我想你会喜欢
- Neat!   - Thought you might like that.
所以我杀了木乃伊和他的手下 然后拿了他的权杖
So then I killed the mummy and all his minions and stole his scepter.
你真勇敢
Oh, you're so brave.
而且富有 我提过吗?
And rich. Did I mention rich?
不然你以为我来干嘛?
What do you think I'm doing here?
抱歉 我们一定是走错了
Sorry. We must be in the wrong house.
你不是说这是你家
You said this was your house.
- 我没说  - 打电话给我
- No, I didn't.   - Call me!
- 你不是席拉的先生吧?  - 不是
- You're not Sheila's husband, are you?   - No.
如果你是强尼的手下 我星期二就会还钱
Look, if you work forJohnny, I was gonna pay him back on Tuesday.
我不认识什么强尼
I don't know any Johnny.
我们在找死神之镯
We are looking for the bracelet of Anubis.
有品位 值得收藏 阿努比斯牌的手镯
Oh, good for you. Good thing to have, the old bracelet of Anubis.
手镯在哪?
Where is it?
你是来找手镯的 原来如此
you're looking here for the bracelet. I see.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
欧康诺先生 我的耐性有限
Mr. O'Connell, you try my patience.
欧康诺先生?等一下 你认错人了
Mr. O'Connell? No, hold on a minute. You've got the wrong ma...
那只手镯 想起来了 我打牌输掉了
That bracelet. Now I remember. I lost it in a card game.
我希望你最好没有
For your sake, I hope not.
不可能
It can't be.
你太太呢?
Where's your wife?
我太太?你是指伊芙
My wife? Oh,you mean Evy.
我想她不是去德国就是去西藏了
I think she went off to Baden-Baden or Tibet or something.
她喜欢到处跑 我提过我单身吗?
The girl's a free spirit. Did I mention I was single now?
埃及眼镜蛇相当的毒
Egyptian asps are quite poisonous.
在楼下
It's downstairs.
有个保险箱 密码是3、20、58...
There's a safe. The combination is, uh, uh, 3-20-58...
393什么的
3-9-3-something.
在楼下保险箱里
It's in a safe downstairs.
我已经说了
I told you. I told you!
你的意思是?
And your point is?
意思是我都说了 你们不能杀我
My point is, I told you so you wouldn't kill me.
我们什么时候答应过?
When did we make that arrangement?
强纳森 跟你说过 不准有疯狂派对的
Jonathan, I thought I said no more wild parties.
受欢迎嘛...
Well, when you're popular...
我是说真的 钥匙丢了你就别想出去
Alex, I'm serious. If you've lost that key, you're grounded.
我没弄丢 我只是找不到 那不一样
I haven't lost it. I just can't find it. There's a difference.
那你最好快点找到
Well, you'd better start finding it then.
我会 妈 别紧张
I will, Mom. There's nothing to worry about.
晚安
Good evening.
你是谁?怎么会在我家?
Who are you? What are you doing here?
我是来找箱子的
I'm looking for the chest, of course.
把箱子给我
Give it to me now.
滚出去 这是我家
Get out of my house.
妈 这主意不太好
Whoa, Mom. Maybe not the best idea.
艾力克斯 到后面去
Alex, get back there.
这主意果然不好
Definitely not the best idea.
我觉得该叫爸来帮忙
I think it's time to yell for Dad now.
那我就杀了你们再拿箱子
Now I will kill you and take it anyway.
不见得
I think not.
阿德贝?你怎么会来?
Ardeth, what are you doing here?
待会儿再解释好了
Perhaps explanations are best kept for later.
阿德贝
Ardeth Bay.
洛克纳
Lock-Nah.
各位 虽然我知道那是他自找的
Knowing my brother-in-law, he probably deserves whatever you're about to do to him,
但这是我家 我不喜欢蛇 也不喜欢死人
but this is my house, I have certain rules about snakes and dismemberment.
杀了他
Shoot him!
哇!妈
Whoa, Mom!
你什么时候学的?
When did you learn to do that?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
这几招是和你爸学的
That I learned from your father.
还给我
I'll take that.
不错嘛!法老侍卫
Not bad for a Medjai.
放手
Let go!
- 箱子里放了什么?  - 死神之镯
- What's in the chest?   - The bracelet of Anubis!
不能让他们拿到
They must not get the bracelet!
快带着箱子走
Get it and get out of here!
妈!小心
Mom, look out!
伊芙琳
Evelyn!
妈
Mom!
强纳森?
Jonathan!
你又做了什么?
What'd you do this time?
我什么都没做
I haven't done anything to anybody!
- 最近吗?  - 快走
- Lately.   - Come on!
瑞克
Rick!
伊芙琳
Evelyn!
小心!
Look out, Rick!
爸 爸
Dad! Dad!
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
- Are you all right?   - Yeah. Yeah? Okay.
欧康诺
O'Connell.
- 你他妈的来干嘛?  - 算了 我不想知道
- What are you doing here?   - No, scratch that. I don't care.
那些是什么人?他们要带我太太去哪?
Who are those guys? Where are they taking my wife?
朋友 我不确定
My friend, I'm not sure,
但是你太太...
but wherever this man is...
一定在他手上
your wife will surely be.
我认得他 他是馆长 大英博物馆的馆长
Hey, I know him. He's the curator. He works at the British Museum.
你确定?
Are you sure?
最好相信他 他在博物馆的时间比在家多
Believe him. He spends more time there than at home.
你来了 坏人也来了 伊芙被绑架 换言之...
You're here, the bad guys are here, Evy's been kidnapped. Let me guess...
对 怪物被他们从墓穴挖了出来
Yes, they once again removed the creature from his grave.
我不是要怪你 你不是应该要看好他的吗?
I don't mean to point fingers, but isn't it your job to make sure that doesn't happen?
和他一起的那个女人知道普通人不可能知道的事
That woman who was with him, she knows things that no living person could possibly know.
她知道怪物确实的埋葬地点
She knew exactly where the creature was buried.
我们希望她会带我们找到手镯 果然没错
We were hoping she would lead us to the bracelet. She obviously did.
现在他们得手了
And now they have it.
我倒不会那么紧张
I wouldn't get too nervous just yet.
那是金的吗?
Is that gold?
我一戴上就看到吉萨的金字塔
When I stuck it on, I saw the pyramids at Giza.
然后"咻"的一声 就越过卡纳克沙漠
Then, whoosh! Straight across the desert to Karnak.
你戴上手镯引起的连锁反应会带来末世的启示录
By putting this on, you have started a chain reaction that could bring the next apocalypse.
- 你 放轻松  - 你 倒霉了
- You, lighten up.   - You, big trouble.
你 上车去
You, get in the car.
抱歉吓到你儿子 但是你必须了解
I am sorry if I alarmed your son, but you must understand,
手镯戴上到魔蝎大帝醒过来 我们只有七天的时间
now that the bracelet is on his wrist, we have only seven days before the Scorpion King awakens.
我们?什么我们?
We? What we?
他要是没死 就会招回阿努比斯的军队
If he is not killed, he will raise the army of Anubis.
八成不是什么好事
I take it that's not a good thing.
是啊!他会消灭全世界
Oh, he'll wipe out the world.
又是"消灭全世界"
The old "wipe out the world" ploy.
杀死魔蝎大帝的人
Whomever can kill the Scorpion King...
可以送他的军队回地府
can send his army back to the Underworld...
或者用他们来消灭人类、统治世界
or use it to destroy mankind and rule the Earth.
他们挖伊莫顿出来 因为他可以干掉魔蝎大帝
That's why they dug up Imhotep. He's the only guy tough enough to take out the Scorpion King.
那就是他们的计划
That is their plan.
大英博物馆
儿子 有重要的工作交给你 留下来保护车子
Alex, I've got a big job for you. Stay here and protect the car.
- 那我可以  - 保护车子?
- I can do that.   - Protect the car?
拜托 我年纪小不表示我笨
Come on Dad, Just because I'm a kid doesn't mean I'm stupid.
我知道
I know.
爸
Dad!
万一看到有人尖叫跑出来 那就是我
If you see anyone come out screaming, it's just me.
你还是留下来陪他好了
Maybe you should stay here and watch him.
你终于想通了
Yes, now you're talking.
你要散弹枪吗?
You want the shotgun?
不 我习惯用机关枪
No, I prefer the Thompson.
如果我对你说...
If I were to say to you,
我是来自东方的陌生人 在找寻我失落的同伴
I'm a stranger traveling from the east, seeking that which is lost...
那我会回答我是来自西方的陌生人
Then I would reply that I am a stranger traveling from the west.
我便是你在找寻的人
It is I whom you seek. How...
这就对了
Then it is true.
- 你手上有圣记  - 这个?
- You have the sacred mark.   - What, that?
这是我在开罗孤儿院被印的
No, that got slapped on me in an orphanage in Cairo.
那个记号表示你是人类的守护者
That mark means you're a protector of man,
上神的战士 法老的侍卫
a warrior for God, a Medjai.
抱歉 你认错人了
Sorry. You've got the wrong guy.
埃及文物区
哈夫兹先生
Mr. Hafez.
他们找到他了
They found him.
苏醒
伊莫顿
Imhotep.
什么时候了?
主人
现在是蝎年
真的?
真的
不要害怕
Do not be frightened.
我一点都不怕
I am not afraid.
我是安苏娜的转世
只是躯体
不过...
我会从地府招回你的魂魄
我们的爱会再次延续
你知道
You know,
几年前 这样的场面会吓我一跳
a couple of years ago, this would've seemed really strange to me.
伊莫顿主人一定会很高兴
Lord Imhotep will be much pleased.
手镯呢?
Where is it?
手镯在哪?
Where is the bracelet?
我知道在哪
I think I know.
在黄金金字塔的顶端 有一颗巨大的钻石
At the very top of the gold pyramid, there was a huge diamond.
有多大?
Huge? How huge?
大到能反射出耀眼的光芒
It was so big, it would reflect the sun
招唤远方的旅客
and wink at distant travelers,
让他们迎向死亡
beckoning them to their deaths.
有份礼物要送给你
是她
我知道你会高兴看到她死
放开我
Get... No! Get off!
天哪!
Oh, my God.
你的死期到了
你等着
You wait!
我会杀了你的
I'll put you in your grave again!
可惜我们打算先杀了你
Our thinking was, not if we put you in your grave first.
烧死她
Burn her!
你混蛋
You bast...
- 快开门啊!  - 我在开啊!
- Open it! Open it!   - I'm trying, I'm trying!
- 快发动  - 快点!快点
- Hurry up!   - Come on, come on, come on!
- 你弄断了  - 别吵
- You broke it, you broke it, you broke it!   - Be quiet, Alex!
惊惶失措是我的专利
If there's gonna be hysterics, they'll come from me!
是你
甲醛 危险
走 走 快走
Go, go, go, go!
聚集你们的骨头
连结你们的肢体
抖落肌肉的尘土
听我号令
老天 不要又是这些家伙
Oh, no. Not these guys again.
消灭他们
现在怎么办?我们怎么办?
What are we gonna do? What are we gonna do?
你问我?我只有8岁耶
You're asking me? I'm only eight years old!
你在干嘛?老婆 他们不用门的
Honey, what you doin'? These guys don't use doors.
强纳森人呢?
Where the hell's Jonathan?
艾力克斯  我的车怎么了?
Alex! What's the matter with my car?
我不得不找其他的交通工具
I was forced to find an alternative means of transportation.
- 双层巴士?  - 是他的主意
- A double-decker bus?   - It was his idea!
- 才不是  - 就是
- Was not!   - Was too!
快开车
Just go!
- 就是  - 不是
- It was too!   - Was not!
天哪!我的车
No, no! Not my car!
我讨厌木乃伊
Oh, I hate mummies.
高兴我在了吧?
Glad to see me now?
就像以前一样?
Just like old times, huh?
转弯 转弯...
Turn! Turn! Turn! Turn! Turn!
天啊!让开
No! Get out of the way!
小心
Look out!
注意桥高
舅舅 开得好
Great driving, Uncle Jon.
是啊!
Yeah.
你没事吧?
You all right?
这是我第一次坐巴士
This was... my first bus ride.
没有你我怎么办?
What would I do without you?
图书馆员都这么麻烦吗?
Are all librarians this much trouble?
拜托 肉麻死了
Jeez, get a room.
放开我
Let me go!
- 别叫  - 放开我
- Silence!   - Stop!
开车
Go!
停下来
Stop!
艾力克斯
Alex.
现在该去阿姆谢
杀死魔蝎大帝
有了他的军队 我们就可以...
一起统治世界
主人
有件事要向您禀告
审判之矛在他们手上
我看到的
等我们到了阿姆谢
我的法力就会恢复
也就不需要审判之矛了
朋友 不要替你儿子担心
Please, do not fear for your son, my friends.
他们不会伤害他的 他戴着死神之镯
They cannot hurt him, for he wears the bracelet of Anubis.
他戴着手镯?
Alex is wearing the bracelet?
他说戴上以后看到吉萨的金字塔、卡纳克的神殿
When he put it on, he said he saw the pyramids at Giza, the temple at Karnak.
等他们到了卡纳克 手镯就会显示下一站
And when they reach Karnak, the bracelet will show him the next step of the journey.
如果不能比他们先到卡纳克 就没办法知道要去哪找他
If we don't get to Karnak before them, we won't have any idea where to look for him next.
看样子
Seems to me
我们需要一张魔毯
like we need a magic carpet.
埃及 开罗
伊莫顿主人和欧康诺最后一次交手的时候
When Lord Imhotep last encountered the O'Connells,
他们害他失去法力 落入地府
they sent his immortal soul to the Underworld.
就算他法力再强 他还是有弱点
As powerful as he will become, he is still vulnerable.
只有阿努比斯的军队才能让他所向无敌
Only with the army of Anubis will he be invincible.
他会需要你帮忙
He will need your help.
随身带着这本书
Keep this with you always.
是亡灵黑经
The Book of the Dead!
好聪明的小朋友
What a bright little child.
你妈妈一定很想你
Your mother must be missing you terribly.
你要想看到她 就要乖乖听话
If you wish to see her again, you'd better behave.
小姐 我爸妈都拿我没辙
Lady, I don't behave for my parents.
你凭什么以为我会听你的?
What makes you think I'm going to do it for you?
闭嘴
Silence!
因为你爸妈不会在你睡觉的时候
Because your parents wouldn't slip poisonous snakes into your bed...
放毒蛇到你床上
while you were sleeping.
伊莫顿主人要见他
Lord Imhotep wishes to meet the boy.
现在我们看看你有多勇敢
Now we shall see how brave you are.
小心我的衣服
Watch the suit! Hey!
我的手指头
Ow! Me fingers!
很好
Nice.
非常好
Very nice.
你拿到我们要的东西没?
Did you acquire what we asked?
我们是拿到了
Oh, we acquired it, all right.
知道吗?
You know what?
我们是杀了两名陵墓守卫才拿到的
We had to kill two of those guards at the mausoleum... to acquire it.
箱子被下了诅咒
This chest is cursed.
上面写着...
It says there is one,
怨灵
the undead,
将杀尽所有开箱之人
who will kill all those who open this chest.
对 而且怪物会吸干他们然后复生
Yes, yes, and the creature will suck them dry, then become whole again.
这故事我们都听过
We've all heard this story before.
但是我听说九年前找到箱子的老美全都死了
Yeah, but I heard the yanks who found it nine years ago all died.
而且死的很惨
Horrible deaths, they were.
所以呢...
So, with that in mind...
我们现在要十万
We want ten.
闭嘴
Quiet!
绝对不能打开箱子
说好了五万的
The agreement was for five.
对 但是我们要十万 不然我们就卖给别人
Yeah, well, we want ten, or we'll take it elsewhere.
- 你敢...  - 十万就十万
- If you...   - Ten will be just fine.
各位 跟我来
Follow me, gentlemen.
进去
Get in.
我知道你听得懂 小鬼
所以你最好听清楚
因为你是被选中的人
it is you who are the chosen one,
要带我去阿姆谢的人
you who will take me to Ahm Shere.
我要是不肯呢?我要是迷路...怎么办?
What if I don't? What if I get a little... lost?
小鬼 你很勇敢
You have strength, little one.
不愧是你爸的儿子 但是有件事你不知道
You are your father's son. But I know something you don't.
这只手镯是一份礼物
This bracelet is a gift
也是一个诅咒
and a curse.
时间的沙
The sands of time...
已经开始从你身上留逝
have already begun to pour against you.
这我早就知道了
Yeah,yeah. I already heard this part.
从我戴上手镯起
From the minute I put the bracelet on,
到魔蝎大帝醒来 我只有七天的时间
seven days do I have before the Scorpion King wakes up.
那你知不知道要是第七天天亮的时候你到不了金字塔
Did you also hear that if you do not enter the pyramid before the...
...sun strikes it on that very morning...
手镯就会要了你的命
that the bracelet will suck the life out of you?
这我倒没听过
That part I missed.
等一下 那我只剩五天的时间了
Hey, wait a minute. That means I've only got five days left.
所以我们最好不要迷路 你说呢?
Then I believe it will be best if we do not get lost. Don't you?
我爸会修理你的
My dad is going to kick your ass.
我不认为
I do not think so.
各位请进 你们会拿到酬劳的
In here, gentlemen, you shall receive your just rewards.
小姐 别耍花样
No tricks now, woman.
你们别想拿箱子 除非我们满意
We're not givin' up this chest till we're satisfied.
别担心 你们一定会非常满意的
Oh, don't worry. There is much satisfaction to be had.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
这个房间...被诅咒了
This place... is cursed.
你有完没完?
What is it with you and curses?
没诅咒你会死啊?
He ain't happy without a curse.
这被诅咒了 那被诅咒了
This is cursed. That is cursed.
你给我闭嘴
Give it a rest, will ya!
老天爷
Christ!
他要你打开箱子 快打开箱子
He wants you to open the chest! Open the chest!
不要
No!
他去哪了?
Where'd he go?
妈呀!
Spivey!
魔毯航空公司
这就是魔毯?
This is the magic carpet?
别担心 他是专家
He'll be fine. He's a professional.
伊西
Izzy!
他果然记得你
He definitely remembers you.
他只是有点害羞 强纳森 去拿行李
He's a little shy. Jonathan, get our bags.
我现在没手拿
Oh, my hands are full.
马上
Now.
行 我去拿行李
Right. I'll get the bags.
我去安排我们的行程
I'll deal with the flight details.
老公 你不是精打细算的人
Honey, you're not a subtle man.
我们没时间精打细算
We don't have time for subtle.
伊西 过来
Izzy, come here.
好像不太想看到你
Doesn't look happy to see you.
还没被他拒绝过
Never turned me down yet.
不管你想干嘛 我都没兴趣 说什么都没用
Whatever it is, whatever you need, I don't care. Forget it, O'Connell.
每次碰到你都要吃子弹
Every time I hook up with you, I get shot!
上次是我的屁股 我心里还是有阴影
Last time, I got shot in the ass. I'm in mourning for my ass.
记得摩洛哥银行的案子吧?
Remember that bank job in Marrakesh?
银行的案子?
Bank job?
不是你想的那样
It's not like it sounds.
就是你想的那样
Uh, it's exactly how it sounds.
我飞高 躲在逆光处
I'm flying high, hiding in the sun.
死白人打信号 叫我飞低接应他
The white boy here flags me down, so I fly in low for the pickup.
下一分钟 我就中弹了
The next thing you know, I get shot!
我躺在路中间 肠子都跑出来了
I'm lying in the middle of the road with my spleen hanging out,
他居然还在旁边和肚皮舞女郎跳舞
and I see him waltzing up with some belly dancer girl.
肚皮舞女郎?
Belly dancer girl?
伊西 我们该好好聊聊
Izzy, I think you and I should talk.
不会吃子弹就行
As long as I don't get shot.
有完没完 这次会付你钱
Quit your whining. You're gonna get paid this time.
拜托你自己看一看 我要钱干嘛?
O'Connell, have you looked around here any? Huh? What do I need money for?
你要我往哪花?
What the hell am I gonna spend it on?
我没时间废话 我儿子不见了
I'm gonna keep this short. My little boy is out there.
无论如何我都要把他找回来
I'm gonna do whatever it takes to get him back.
只要有金棍子 你想干嘛就干嘛
O'Connell, if you give me that gold stick there, you can shave my head,
你要我剃光头、刮腿毛都行
wax my legs and use me for a surfboard.
在的黎波里不是干过吗?
Didn't we do that in Tripoli?
对了 你的眼睛怎么瞎的?
Say, by the way, when did you... lose your eye?
我没瞎 只是觉得这样比较有味道
I didn't. I just thought it made me look more dashing.
快点 去准备
Come on. Get to work.
我平常不是这样的
You're not exactly catching me at my best.
我相信
Oh, I'm sure I am.
我就知道 又要吃子弹了
I knew it. I'm gonna get shot.
他们是十二支法老侍卫队的队长
These are the commanders of the 12 tribes of the Medjai.
霍勒斯
Horus!
宠物鸟
Pet bird.
我最好也是最聪明的朋友
My best and most clever friend.
它会让队长们知道我们的位置
He will let the commanders know of our progress so that they may follow.
万一阿努比斯的军队复活
If the Army of Anubis arises,
他们一定会尽全力阻止的
they will do all they can to stop it.
你确定伊西可靠吗?
Rick, are you sure Izzy's reliable?
可靠 当然可靠...但愿
Yeah, yeah, he's reliable-ish.
漂亮吧?
Isn't she beautiful?
怎么是气球
It's a balloon.
是飞船
It's a dirigible.
你的飞机呢?
Where's your airplane?
飞机早就落伍了
Airplanes are a thing of the past.
- 伊西 你是对的  - 我是?
- Izzy, you were right.   - I was?
你要吃子弹了
Yeah. You're gonna get shot.
它比你想像的要快
She's faster than she looks.
而且非常安静
And she's quiet. Real quiet.
非常适合偷袭 这是最好的一点
Perfect for sneaking up on people, which is a very good thing.
除非 我们要用你的方法
Unless, of course, we go with your approach...
先冲进去 然后一阵扫射 害你朋友屁股中弹
barging in face-first, guns blazing, and gettin' your friends shot in the ass!
为什么你们就是要搞这么多飞机呢?
Why can't you people ever keep your feet on the ground?
欧康诺不肯相信 但是他正飞向他的命运
O'Connell does not want to believe, but he flies like Horus towards his destiny.
没错 非常有趣 告诉我黄金金字塔的事
Yes, yes, very interesting. Tell me some more about this gold pyramid.
根据记载 从魔蝎大帝的时代到现在
Well, it is written that since the time of the Scorpion King,
看过金字塔的人没有一个活着回来
no man who has laid eyes upon it has ever returned to tell the tale.
这些事都写在哪?太好了
Where is all this stuff written? Hello.
拿到了
Got it.
很漂亮吧?
Pretty nice, eh?
这是我唯一剩下的
This is all I have left in the world.
其他的财产都输掉了
The rest of my fortune was lost...
是被一些无耻小人赢走的
to some rather unscrupulous characters, actually.
馆长的反应要真像你说的那样 那它一定非常重要
But if the curator reacted to it the way you say, it must be very important.
我是你 我会随身带着
If I were you, I would keep it close.
朋友 神都别想把这玩意拿走
My friend, the gods couldn't take this away from me.
- 这是我的  - 才不是
- That's mine!   - No, it's not!
把你的手拿开
Keep your hands off of it.
瑞克 我好想他
I want him back, Rick.
我要他回到我身边来
I want him in my arms.
我知道
I know.
他很独立
We taught him well.
他比你还聪明
He's smarter than you...
比我还坚强
and he's tougher than me.
- 我太爱他 我就是...  - 我知道 我们都很爱他
- I love him so much. I just can't...   - I know. We both do,
儿子也知道
and Alex knows that.
我保证 我会把他找回来的
I'll get him back, Evy. I promise.
我知道你会
I know you will.
- 到了没?  - 还没...
- Are we there yet? Are we there yet?   - No. No.
好厉害哦!瞄的真准
That was amazing! Perfect aim.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我瞄歪了
I missed.
我想上厕所
I have to go to the bathroom.
上快点
Make it quick.
快点
Hurry up.
- 还有厕所文学  - 快点
- Hey, reading material.   - Now!
有人看着我尿不出来
I can't go when someone's watching.
我不相信你 你会偷看
I don't trust you. You'll look.
可恶
Darn!
脏死了
Oh, my God!
难道没有人知道怎么冲马桶吗?
Doesn't anyone around here know how to flush a toilet?
小鬼
卡纳克
Karnak.
不能接受过去的人 就没有未来
If a man does not embrace his past, he has no future.
听着
Look,
就算...
even if...
我曾经是法老的侍卫好了
I was some sort of sacred Medjai,
那和现在又有什么关系呢?
what good does that do me now?
那是你的一部分
It is the missing piece of your heart.
你只要接受过去 没有什么可以难得倒你
If you embrace it, if you accept it, you can do anything.
听起来不错
Sounds great.
还有 我们该怎么对付伊莫顿
Listen. What can we expect from our old friend Imhotep?
他法力恢复的很快
His powers are returning.
等他到了阿姆谢 恐怕连魔蝎大帝都杀不了他
By the time he reaches Ahm Shere, even the Scorpion King won't be able to stop him.
该记起你的过去了
记起我们的过去
我们的真爱
永恒的爱
我们的灵魂
相偎相依
直到永远
把面具带上
别划花你美丽的脸
娜菲迪莉 你学的很快
我该小心点了
没错
我也会小心的
精采!精采!
守护死神之镯的最佳人选
我可爱的女儿 娜菲迪莉
保护我的最佳人选
我未来的妻子 安苏娜
女儿 打得好
法老
侍卫
我父亲需要你们
你快走!不要管我
不!
只有你才能让我复活
我不能丢下你
滚开
安苏娜
伊莫顿
Imhotep.
我的身体已经另有所属
伊莫顿
Imhotep.
安苏娜
Anck-su-namun.
我知道那些梦和幻觉让你最近变得怪怪的
Evy, I know you haven't exactly been yourself lately with all these dreams and visions...
不 那些是我前世的记忆
No, no, they're memories from my previous life.
我是说真的 我现在终于明白了
Honestly, I'm not losing my mind. It all makes perfect sense now.
所以我们才能找到手镯?
And that's the reason why we found the bracelet?
没错 我是手镯的守护人
Exactly. I was its protector.
现在你相信了吧?朋友
Now do you believe, my friend?
冥冥中注定 你是来保护她的
Clearly, you were destined to protect this woman.
对啊!她是转世的公主 我是上神的战士
Right. She's a reincarnated princess, and I'm a warrior for God.
而你儿子是到阿姆谢的向导 像金字塔的三面
And your son leads the way to Ahm Shere. Three sides of the pyramid.
这都是前世注定的
This was all preordained thousands of years ago.
故事的结局呢?
And how does the story end?
只有写过程 没有写结局
Only the journey's written, not the destination.
偷懒
Convenient.
不然你怎么解释伊芙的幻觉?
How else do you explain Evy's visions?
为什么是你儿子戴上手镯?
That it is your son who wears the bracelet?
你怎么解释你手腕的记号?
How do you explain your mark?
巧合
Coincidence.
朋友 巧合和命运只有一线之隔
My friend, there is a fine line between coincidence and fate.
别玩花样
Don't even think about it!
别乱来 老兄
Hold on there, partner.
等时间到了
When the time comes,
我会非常乐意杀了你
I shall truly enjoy killing you.
但是在那之前
But until that time,
你最好对我好一点
you better be a little nicer to me.
我的水在哪?
Now, where's my water?
冰块呢?
No ice?
不准他乱跑
Make sure he doesn't move!
他们走了 我们慢了一步
They've gone. We've lost them.
瑞克
Rick!
艾力克斯留下了领带
Alex left us his tie,
还堆了一座沙堡给我们
and he made us a little sand castle.
是菲莱神殿岛
It's the Temple Island of Philae.
他们去菲莱了
They've gone to Philae. That-a-boy, Alex.
好孩子 我们走
Come on!
阿布新贝尔神殿
The great temple of Abu Simbel.
下面是蓝色尼罗河 我们已经出了埃及
That's the Blue Nile down there. We must be out of Egypt by now.
在远古时代 这些都是上埃及的范围
In ancient times, all this still belonged to the upper kingdom.
绿洲应该就在附近
The oasis must be around here somewhere.
别担心 我们会找到他的
Don't worry, Evy, we'll find him.
他那么聪明 会留记号给我们的
He's a smart kid. He'll leave us a sign.
吓了你一跳?
Surprised to see me?
居然在留记号?
Leaving bread crumbs, huh? Huh?
洛克纳
放他下来
希望你父母的旅途愉快
麻烦来啦!
We're in trouble!
霍勒斯 去
Horus, fly!
伊西 快往右转 右舵 转右舵
Izzy, come hard right! Starboard! Starboard!
你们是不是有事情忘了告诉我?
Was there a little something you forgot to mention? Hmm?
各位
People?
阿姆谢
Ahm Shere.
没错
Right.
又来啦!
He's back!
抓稳
Hang on!
糟糕了
Well, that's not good.
抓稳
Hang on!
妈
Mom?
爸
Dad?
我们要找到我儿子
We're gonna go get my son.
然后要尽快离开这里 你最好想办法修好
Then we're gonna wanna get out of here fast, so make this work, Izzy.
你搞清楚 这东西靠瓦斯 不是热气 是瓦斯
No, no, you don't understand, goddamn it. This thing was filled with gas. Not hot air... gas.
我需要瓦斯才有办法飞起来 你要我去哪找瓦斯来?
I need gas to get this thing off the ground. Where am I gonna get gas from around here? Huh?
香蕉?芒果?还是泰山的屁股
Bananas? Mangos? Tarzan's ass?
我也许可以改用热空气
Well, maybe I could finagle it to take hot air.
但是你知道我需要多少吗?根本不可能嘛
But do you know how many cubic meters I'd need? It's too big!
我知道你一定有办法 我对你有信心
If anybody can fill this thing up with hot air, Izzy, it's you.
回来吧!
Come to Daddy.
霍勒斯
Horus!
瑞克 现在怎么办?
So, Rick, what's the plan?
我们先找一块高地
Let's find some higher ground.
霍勒斯
Horus!
- 我非走不可  - 去哪?
- I must go.   - Where?
- 去通知队长我们在哪  - 你不能走
- I must let the commanders know where we are.   - You can't go.
万一阿努比斯的军队复活...
If the Army of Anubis arises...
我需要你帮忙找我儿子
I need you to help me find my son.
那我先帮你找
Then first, I shall help you.
谢谢
Thank you.
看 罗马军团
Look. Roman legionnaires.
这边 18世纪的法国人 拿破仑的军队
And here. Turn-of-the-century French. Napoleon's troops.
全是阿努比斯干的?
What in the name of Anubis did this?
听到没?
You hear that?
什么?
What?
没事
Nothing.
没什么事
Absolutely nothing.
我的妈!
My word!
你们快来看
I say, chaps, look at this.
缩水的头 真想知道他们是怎么弄的
Shrunken heads. I'd love to know how they do that.
随便说说
Just curious.
你会用枪吗?
You any good with that?
三届的猎狐大赛总冠军 你会用刀吗?
Three times Fox and Hound's grand champion, I'll have you know. You any good with that?
你很快就知道了
You'll know soon enough.
杀死阿努比斯战士唯一的方法是砍掉他的头
Because the only way to kill an Anubis warrior is by taking off its head.
我会记得
I'll remember that.
记住...
Evy, try to remember to, uh...
枪托要抵紧肩膀
Just keep it tight in the shoulder and, uh,
事先瞄准目标 然后...
lead the target a little bit, and then, uh...
扣板机 不要用拉的
And squeeze the trigger. Don't pull it.
我会瞄准的
I won't miss.
金字塔
pyramid.
天啊!这下麻烦大了
Cripes, I'm in trouble now.
现在可以杀他了吧?
Now may I kill him?
主人
现在不需要小男孩了
对 但是我们需要手镯
要用它来释放阿努比斯的军队
手镯?
钥匙就是手镯?
- 把手镯拿来  - 没问题
- Retrieve that bracelet.   - With pleasure.
怎么了?
有东西靠近
Something is coming.
散开
张大眼镜
提高警觉
强纳森
Jonathan?
我丈夫和儿子都在下面
That's my husband and my son down there.
不要让我失望
Make me proud.
放心 包在我身上
Today's that day, Evy.
别怕 他们伤不了我
小孩呢?
Where's the boy?
拿着!
The Black Book!
我们走
Let's go!
找到了
There you are!
小朋友 时间到了
The time has come, my little friend.
放手
Let go!
爸
Dad!
艾力克斯
Alex!
爸
Dad!
该脱手镯了 小鬼
Time to remove that bracelet, my good son.
爸
Dad!
后面
behind you!
我们走
Let's go.
谢天谢地
Thank God for that.
你们要牺牲自己来保护我
The two of you must sacrifice yourselves for me.
神会奖励你们的
You shall be rewarded in heaven!
- 妈  - 艾力克斯
- Mom!   - Alex!
老兄 好枪法
Hey, nice shootin', Tex.
那些小矮人是干嘛的?
What were those creepy little pygmy things?
只是当地的土人
Just the local natives.
- 你确定?  - 我确定 没什么
- Are you sure?   - I'm sure. It was nothin'.
爸、妈 快点 我们快去金字塔
Come on, Mom! Come on! Come on, Dad! We have to get to the pyramid.
我要快点脱掉手镯
I have to get the bracelet off now!
别脱了 戴起来很好看
Oh, leave it on, Alex. Looks good on you.
不行 你们不明白
No, you guys! You don't understand!
天亮前到不了金字塔我就死定了
He told me the bracelet will kill me if I don't get inside the pyramid before the sun hits it!
就是今天
Today!
我的天
Oh, my God.
该走了
Time to go!
你不是说没什么吗?
I thought you said it was nothing!
强纳森呢?
Where's Jonathan?
你看 这里是埋葬场 我们安全了!
Look! There's a burial ground! We're safe! We're safe!
他们越不过这些圣石的
See those sacred stones? They'll never cross those.
你确定?
You are sure?
我当然确定
Yes, of course I'm sure!
对不起 弄错了
Sorry. My mistake.
等等我!
Wait for me!
强纳森 快点
Hurry up,Jonathan!
等等我
Wait for me!
那是干嘛的?
What's that for?
这是用来以防万一的
Ah, nothin'. Just a little something in case of an emergency.
瑞克
Rick.
儿子 我们走
Let's go, Alex!
跑 快点 快跑
Run! Come on, Alex, faster! Come on!
爸 手镯
Dad! The bracelet!
快点 快点
Run! Come on!
你知道...
You know,
当爸爸...不容易
it's not easy being a... dad.
对啊!但是你当的很好
Yeah, but you do it really good.
谢了
Thanks.
他们到了 谢天谢地
They made it. Thank God.
是啊!好极了
Yes. Great.
真是太棒了
Fabulous.
不!
No!
伊芙
Evy!
她不会有事的 对不对?  她不会有事的
-You're going to be all right. Isn't she, Dad? She's going to be all right.-She'll be fine.
帮我看着他
Just get him... Take him. Take...
妈妈不会有事的 没事
Mommy's fine. It's okay.
你妈不会有事的 别担心
Where... Evy... Your mother's gonna be fine, okay?
你那么坚强 你不会有事的
You're real strong. You're gonna make it. You're gonna make it.
你会好的
You're fine.
我该怎么办?
What do I do?
我该怎么办?伊芙
What do I do, Evy?
照顾好儿子
Take care of Alex.
亲爱的 不要
Sweetheart, no.
我爱你
I love you.
不要离开我 不要
No, don't... No. No!
伊芙
Evy? Evy?
醒醒 伊芙
Come back, Evy.
醒醒啊!
Come back.
你醒醒
巨神阿努比斯...
收走了我的法力
看来他希望我以凡人的身份...
来决斗
你留下来
Stay here.
终于开始了
艾力克斯 试着往好处想
Try to think of it like this, Alex.
她到更好的地方去了
She's gone to a better place.
- 就像书上说的那本书  - 那本书
- You know, like it says in the good book.   - The book!
- 什么?  - 我想到了
- What?   - That's it.
- 我想到了  - 想到什么了?
- That's it.   - That's what?
- 快点 舅舅 我想到了 那本书  - 什么?
- Come on, Uncle Jon! Come on! Come on! That's it! The book!   - What?
来不及了 欧康诺
You're too late, O'Connell.
我已经释放了阿努比斯的军队
I have released the Army of Anubis.
主人会杀了魔蝎大帝 然后控制一切
Lord Imhotep shall soon kill the Scorpion King and take command.
他过得了我这关再说
Not after I get through with him.
我必须单独面对魔蝎大帝
不 不要去
你没有法力杀不死他的
谁都不能阻止我们
这是我们的命运
我不要再失去你
当然 你该知道
You realize, of course,
要能读古埃及文才能招魂
that this can only be done by someone who can actually read ancient Egyptian.
我是不知道你怎样 但我是有点生疏
I don't know about you, but I'm a tad rusty.
现在呢?
Now where?
往右
We go right.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
意思是 此路通魔蝎大帝
Basically, "This way to the Scorpion King."
妈教我的
Mum taught me.
我们有希望了
This just might work.
死女人 该有人教训你一顿
It's time someone taught you a lesson, wench. Come on.
我要为我妹妹报仇
This is for my sister.
你想杀了我?
然后你想杀了他
送他的军队回地府
我绝对不答应
你没吃饭吗?
Is that all you've got?
快点 艾力克斯
Hurry up, Alex!
舅舅 我看不懂最后一个符号
Uncle Jon, I don't know what this last symbol is!
看起来像什么?
What's it look like?
是一只鸟 一只鹤
It's a bird! A stork!
我知道 那个我知道
I know that one! I know that one!
到底是什么?
Then what is it?
没错
That's it!
欺负男人你不丢脸吗?
Why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
我的天
Oh, my God.
伊芙 带艾力克斯走
Evy! Take Alex.
- 去帮瑞克  - 妈 可是...
- Go and help Rick.   - But Mom...
- 没有"可是"  - 我们走
- No "buts," Alex.   - Come on, Alex.
我不会有事的
I'll be just fine.
舅舅 我们成功了
We did it, Uncle Jon! We did it!
没错 现在我们去帮你爸
Right, partner. Now, let's go help your dad.
我是你的仆人
再看吧!
他是来杀你的
娜菲迪莉
Nefertiri.
安苏娜
Anck-su-namun.
很好
你恢复以前的身手了
这是新招数
That's a little something new!
主人
My lord!
救我!快救我
Save me! Save me!
为什么?
神啊!救救我们!
好 现在我信了
Okay, now I'm a believer.
瑞克
Rick!
强纳森
Jonathan!
那是矛
It's a spear!
那根金色的棍子 是一支矛
The gold stick thing... It's a... It's a spear!
真的?看起来不像啊!
Really? Doesn't look like a spear!
那是因为要转开才是
No! That's because it opens up into one!
是吗?然后呢?
Yes? And?
强纳森 转开 就会变成一根矛
Jonathan! It opens up into a spear!
奋战到底!
瑞克
Rick!
伊芙
Evy?
- 用力转 然后再推  - 我试过了!
- Twist it! Pull!   - I tried it!
你要用拉的
Push!
审判之矛
Jonathan, quick!
强纳森 快点
Jonathan, Come on
强纳森 快射他 杀了魔蝎大帝
Jonathan, throw it! Kill the Scorpion King!
送他的军队回地府
Send his army back to the Underworld!
站到旁边去 我可是专家
Step aside, Alex. I'm a professional.
阿努比斯的军队是我的了
瑞克
Rick!
不!
No!
去死吧!叫你的朋友一起去
Go to hell, and take your friends with you!
爸
Dad!
伊芙
Evy,
快走 快点走 不要管我
no! Get out of here! Just get out of here!
不
No!
妈
Mom!
瑞克 撑着
Hang on, Rick!
安苏娜
Anck-su-namun.
救我!
安苏娜
Anck-su-namun.
往上爬
Let's go up!
金字塔要沉下去了 我们往上爬!走
This whole damn place is gonna get sucked up! Let's move up! Go!
艾力克斯 快
Go, Alex! Come on! Come on!
瑞克 没路走了
Rick, we're trapped!
伊西
Izzy!
快上来 动作快 时间不多了
Come on! Get your butts moving! Hurry up! Hurry up! I haven't got all day!
轮到你 快
Go! You're next!
强纳森 撑住
Jonathan! Hold on!
快拉他上来!快拉
Pull him up! Pull him up!
拉我上去!拉我上去
Pull up! Pull me up!
等一下 等一下 放我下去 放我下去
Wait! Wait! Let me down! Let me down!
那不值得你去死 你疯了
It's not worth your life, you idiot!
值得 绝对值得
Yes, it is! Yes, it is!
行了
Right.
拉我上去!拉我上去
Pull me up! Pull me up!
欧康诺 我差点被你害死
O'Connell. You almost got me killed!
至少你没吃子弹
At least you didn't get shot.
伊西
Izzy!
谢谢你 谢谢你
Thank you! Thank you!
欧康诺 你这次又惹到谁了
O'Connell, who the hell you been messin' with this time? Huh?
你知道 还不就那些
Oh, you know, the usual.
木乃伊、小矮人
Mummies, pygmies,
大虫子
big bugs.
我以为我失去了你
I thought I almost lost you there.
你是失去了一下子
For a moment there, you did.
想知道天堂是什么样子吗?
Would you like to know what heaven looks like?
晚点再说
Later
拜托!拜托!
Oh, please!
- 老兄 那一半是我的  - 什么?
- That's half mine, you know.   - What?
- 那一半是我的  - 我不知道你在说什么?
- That's half mine.   - I have no idea what you're talking about.
你拿了我的金棍子
What? You took my gold stick! I know you took my gold stick!
我用我太太的头发誓 我不知道你在说什么
I swear on the head of my wife, I have no idea what you're talking about.
你根本就没太太
You haven't... You ain't got a wife!
我也没拿你的金棍子
I don't have your gold stick either!
木乃伊2